JINESH BABU K S

HEAD- MERCHANDISING/MARKETING

jineshbabuks@gmail.com 🔀

+91 8754449557

Kannur, Kerala, India 👂

linkedin.com/in/jinesh-babu-0171457 in

SUMMARY

21 Yrs of experience in Knits/Wovens in Merchandising/Production planning coordination/Sourcing in Garment Manufacturing Industry in India. Resourceful in driving and managing planning and merchandising activities for achieving on time delivery and efficiency. Good commercial skills in vendor development, materials management, inventory control.

Has efficiently handled buyers like Calvin Klein, Tomy Hilfiger, LC Waikiki, Migros, Monoprix, Galleries Lafayette, Gerber, ToysRus, Mothercare, Carters (Kids wear), M&S, Habitat, JTex, Muji (Home furnishing), C&A, Kohls, Reitmans, Woolworths, Aeropostale, (Men's & Ladies wear) Jockey (Under Garments), Spykar, Van Heusen, Peter England.

An effective communicator with polished leadership, relationship management, planning, coordination and analytical skills.

SKILLS

Reliability	• • • •	Problem Solving	• • • • •
Multi Tasking	••••	Customer	••••
Communication		relationship	
Interpersonal Skills		Team Work	• • • • •

EXPERIENCE

BUSINESS HEAD

AKR Industries Pvt Ltd Nov 2021 - Present

Buyers Handled – Calvin Klein, Tommy Hilfiger, C&A, LC Waikiki, M&A, OVS, Nautica, etc

Team Leader

All Merchandising Activites

Costing

Product Development

Responsible for business and execution

Divisional Merchandising Manager

Sakthi Infra Tex Pvt Ltd Oct 2017 - Oct 2021

Buyers Handled - LUCKY BRAND, REITMANS, ZUMIEZ, SANMAR, AEROPOSTALE, MONOPRIX, MIGROS, WOOLWORTHS, NORDSTORM, CYRILLUS,

Team Leader

Costng, All merchandising/Production Activites

Sr. Manager, Merchandising

P S Apparels Pvt Ltd Oct 2015 - Oct 2017 Buyers handled- REITMANS, ZUMIEZ, KOHLS.

Do planning from fabric to shipment.

Do co-ordination between each department to achieve shipment on time.

Do Communication with customers/Buyer

All the merchandising jobs and involve in Production planning

Asst Manager Sourcing & Merchandisng

Blue Sky Apparels Pvt Ltd Oct 2011 - Sep 2015

Partnership with Aditya Birla group to source for the brands Van Heusen and Peter England

Style allocation, price Negotiation, approvals, planning, production follow up,

All other merchandising activities and coordination with supply chain department.

Asst Manager Planning

Kitex Garments Pvt Ltd Nov 2006 - Sep 2011

Buyers handled-GERBER, TOYS RUS, MOTHER CARE, JOCKEY, CARTERS.

To plan the whole production and follow up the production which is going as per planning.

Line Planning, Group planning, Embroidery Planning, Container planning, Cutting Dept planning, Etc, and doing interaction with buyers and give commitment and work to meet that.

Do coordination between merchandising team and production team. All production planning and Control activities (PPC), and coordination with merchandising and production to get into on time schedule

Sr Merchandiser

Dhanalakshmi Weaving Works Jun 2002 - Sep 2006 Buyers handled – MUJI, J TEX, MARKS & SPENCER, and HABITAT.

Being interface between buyers and the company, I was able to understand needs precisely and able to revert back to the buyer with perfection, To be highly organized, with a good knowledge in costing ,fabrics and made up, Being a merchandiser involves a lengthy responsibility of purchasing fabric, trims and making a garment, Making of new products and its presentation, Collects some knowledge of current trends and fashions

PROJECTS

- Attended in a training program conducted by South Indian Textile Research Association(SITRA) to develop the textile knowledge and skills
- Attended in a training program conducted by Kerala Productivity Council to improve the managerial and Supervisory skills

EDUCATION

Diploma in TextleTechnology

Govt Poly technic, Kannur *Jun 1999 - Apr 2002* With 70%

BCA

IGNOU *May 2004 - Mar 2008* With 68%

Pre Degree

Sir Syed College, Kannur Jun 1996 - Mar 2006 With 63%

SSLC

Board of Educations, Kerala *Mar 1996* With 80%

PERONNEL DETAILS

• Nationality : Indian • Date of birth : 09.04.1982 Sex : Male • Marital Status : Married • Passport No : F7534297

LANGUAGES

Malayalam

Hindi English Tamil

HOBBIES

Cricket Driving

Reading Music

DECLERATION I hereby declare that the above-mentioned statements are best and true to my

knowledge

Faithfully

Jinesh Babu K S